<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>H. Zhang | Welcome</title>
    <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/h.-zhang/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tfeng7.github.io/author/h.-zhang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>H. Zhang</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tfeng7.github.io/images/icon_hu9dc07378506dda20152aae5397c06783_79375_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>H. Zhang</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/h.-zhang/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of Tropical Cyclone Activity over the South China Sea: Local and Nonlocal Tropical Cyclones.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-tao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, J.-M. Chen, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2020: Characteristics of Tropical Cyclone Activity over the South China Sea: Local and Nonlocal Tropical Cyclones. &lt;em&gt;Terrestrial, Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt;, 261-271, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3319/TAO.2019.07.01.02&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3319/TAO.2019.07.01.02&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The upper ocean thermodynamic and biological responses to two sequential tropical cyclones (TCs) over the Northwestern Pacific Ocean were investigated using multi-satellite datasets, in situ observations and numerical model outputs. During Kalmaegi and Fung-Wong, three distinct cold patches were observed at sea surface. The locations of these cold patches are highly correlated with relatively shallower depth of the 26 °C isotherm and mixed layer depth (MLD) and lower upper ocean heat content. The enhancement of surface chlorophyll a (chl-a) concentration was detected in these three regions as well, mainly due to the TC-induced mixing and upwelling as well as the terrestrial runoff. Moreover, the pre-existing ocean cyclonic eddy (CE) has been found to significantly modulate the magnitude of surface cooling and chl-a increase. With the deepening of the MLD on the right side of TCs, the temperature of the mixed layer decreased and the salinity increased. The sequential TCs had superimposed effects on the upper ocean response. The possible causes of sudden track change in sequential TCs scenario were also explored. Both atmospheric and oceanic conditions play noticeable roles in abrupt northward turning of the subsequent TC Fung-Wong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ning, J., Q. Xu*, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, H. Zhang, T. Wang, 2019: Upper Ocean Response to Two Sequential Tropical Cyclones over the Northwestern Pacific Ocean. &lt;em&gt;Remote Sensing&lt;/em&gt;, 11, 2431, doi:10.3390/rs11202431.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-sces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-sces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2018 typhoon season in the western North Pacific (WNP) was highly active, with 26 named tropical cyclones (TCs) from June to November, which exceeded the climatological mean (22) and was the second busiest season over the past twenty years. More TCs formed in the eastern region of the WNP and the northern region of the South China Sea (SCS). More TCs took the northeast quadrant in the WNP, recurving from northwestward to northward and causing heavy damages in mainland China (69.73 billion yuan) in 2018. Multiscale climate variability is conducive to an active season via an enhanced monsoon trough and a weakened subtropical high in the WNP. The large-scale backgrounds in 2018 showed a favorable environment for TCs established by a developing central Pacific (CP) El Niño and positive Pacific meridional mode (PMM) episode on interannual timescales. The tropical central Pacific (TCP) SST forcing exhibits primary control on TCs in the WNP and large-scale circulations, which are insensitive to the PMM. During CP El Niño years, anomalous convection associated with the TCP warming leads to significantly increased anomalous cyclonic circulation in the WNP because of a Gill-type Rossby wave response. As a result, the weakened subtropical high and enhanced monsoon trough shift eastward and northward, which favor TC genesis and development. Although such increased TC activity in 2018 might be slightly suppressed by interdecadal climate variability, it was mostly attributed to the favorable interannual background. In addition, high-frequency climate signals, such as intraseasonal oscillations (ISOs) and synoptic-scale disturbances (SSDs), interacted with the enhanced monsoon trough and strongly modulated regional TC genesis and development in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;*, and Y. Tang, 2019: Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018. &lt;em&gt;Sci. China Earth Sci.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11430-019-9474-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11430-019-9474-4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Two Types of El Niño on Tropical Cyclones over the Western North Pacific: Sensitivity to Location and Intensity of Pacific Warming</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present study investigates the impact of various central Pacific (CP) and eastern Pacific (EP) warming on tropical cyclones (TCs) over the western North Pacific (WNP) for the period 1948–2015 based on observational and reanalysis data. Four distinctly different forms of tropical Pacific warming are identified to examine different impacts of locations and intensity of tropical Pacific warming on the WNP TCs. It is shown that WNP TC activity related to ENSO shows stronger sensitivity to the intensity of CP SST warming. The locations of TC genesis in an extreme EP El Niño featuring concurrent strong CP and EP warming (CEPW) display a notable southeastward shift that is generally similar to the CP El Niño featuring CP warming alone (CPW). These influences are clearly different from the effects of moderate EP El Niño associated with EP warming alone (EPW). The above influences of Pacific warming on TCs possibly occur via atmospheric circulation variability. Anomalous convection associated with CP SST warming drives anomalous low-level westerlies away from the equator as a result of a Gill-type Rossby wave response, leading to an enhanced broad-zone, eastward-extending monsoon trough (MT). An anomalous Walker circulation in response to EP SST warming drives an increase in anomalous equatorial westerlies over the WNP, leading to a narrow-zone, slightly equatorward shift of the eastward-extending MT. These changes in the MT coincide with a shift in large-scale environments and synoptic-scale perturbations, which favor TC genesis and development. In addition, during weaker EP SST warming (WEPW) with similar intensity to CPW, local SST forcing exhibits primary control on WNP TCs and atmospheric circulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, J.-M. Chen, and &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018: Impact of Two Types of El Niño on Tropical Cyclones over the Western North Pacific: Sensitivity to Location and Intensity of Pacific Warming. &lt;em&gt;J. Climate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt;, 1725–1742, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-17-0298.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-17-0298.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
