<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C. Chu | Welcome</title>
    <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/c.-chu/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tfeng7.github.io/author/c.-chu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>C. Chu</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tfeng7.github.io/images/icon_hu9dc07378506dda20152aae5397c06783_79375_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>C. Chu</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/c.-chu/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reexamination of the climatology and variability of the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific using a daily index</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-jc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-jc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study developed a daily index to represent the northwest Pacific monsoon trough using westerly related cyclonic vorticity after removing tropical cyclones (TCs) from the reanalysis dataset. This index sufficiently captures the spatial and temporal variations in the monsoon trough. The use of this daily index revealed new features in the monsoon trough, including daily statistical characteristics, the active period over a year, and the main periodicity. A monsoon trough can be identified as active when the daily index is greater than $2.0×10^{-4} s^{-1}$. Active monsoon troughs occur during half of the summertime, and these is no monsoon trough on one-third of days, with the remaining days categorized as inactive. The most active month is August, in which approximately twenty days exhibit an active monsoon trough. Using this index, an active monsoon trough period, which is related to vigorous TC activity, was determined by identifying the establishment and decay dates for each year from 1979 to 2016. During most years, the active monsoon trough is established in mid-July and decays in late October, persisting for three to five months during the boreal summer. Moreover, spectral and wavelet analyses demonstrated the presence of intraseasonal, interannual and interdecadal variabilities in the monsoon trough. The dominant periodicity for the interannual variability varied from 1.5 to 4 years in different decades.The relationship between the monsoon trough and TCs are also revealed using this index, that approximately 60% of TC formations were related to an active monsoon trough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feng T.&lt;/strong&gt;*, X.-Q. Yang, X. Sun, D. Yang, C. Chu, 2020. Reexamination of the climatology and variability of the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific using a daily trough index.  &lt;em&gt;Journal of Climate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-19-0459.1.5&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-19-0459.1.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reply to Comment by Michael K. Tippett on “On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.”</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-jgra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-jgra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tippett (2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD029345&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD029345&lt;/a&gt;) provides an insightful comment on the theoretical consideration part of Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002),&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002),&lt;/a&gt; which studied the relationship between probabilistic and deterministic skills in dynamical seasonal climate prediction. The author connects the theoretical finding of Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;) with some previous studies on this topic and further provide a simple‐form approximation to the derived theoretical relation in Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002)&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002)&lt;/a&gt;. However, the author also indicates the difference between the considerations in Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;) and the previous studies. In this reply, we present a detailed explanation to the readers of the difference between these considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang, D., X.-Q. Yang*, D. Ye, X. Sun, J. Fang, C. Chu, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Jiang, J. Liang, X. Ren, Y. Zhang, Y. Tang, 2019: Reply to Comment by Michael K. Tippett on “On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;124&lt;/strong&gt;, 3982–3983, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD030289&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD030289&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jgra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jgra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the gradually increasing emphasis on assessing the skill of dynamical seasonal climate predictions from the probabilistic perspective, there is a lack of in‐depth understanding that an inherent relationship may exist between the probabilistic and deterministic seasonal forecast skills. In this study, we focus on investigating this relationship, through theoretical consideration based on an analytical approach and diagnostic analysis of the historical forecasts produced by multiple dynamical models. The probabilistic forecast skill is gauged in terms of its two different attributes: resolution and reliability, while the deterministic forecast skill is measured in terms of anomaly correlation (AC). Through the theoretical consideration under certain simplified assumptions, a nonlinear, monotonic relationship is analytically derived between the resolution and the AC. Subsequent diagnostic analysis shows that the resolution and AC skills of both the multimodel ensemble and its member single models indeed appear to be approximately monotonically and nonlinearly related, specifically when they are calculated in a zonally aggregated manner by which the impact of finite sample size is reduced. This observed relationship has a specific form that is consistent with what the theory predicts. In short, the theoretical result is well verified by the dynamical model forecasts. Diagnostic analysis also shows that no good relationship exists between the reliability and the AC, signifying the difference of reliability and resolution in nature. A specific application of the proven resolution‐AC coherence is also demonstrated. The proved resolution‐AC relationship can facilitate comparisons among various assessments of seasonal climate prediction skill from the deterministic or probabilistic perspective alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang, D., X.-Q. Yang*, D. Ye, X. Sun, J. Fang, C. Chu, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Jiang, J. Liang, X. Ren, Y. Zhang, Y. Tang, 2018: On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;123&lt;/strong&gt;, 5261–5283, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
