<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Y. Jiang | Welcome</title>
    <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/y.-jiang/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tfeng7.github.io/author/y.-jiang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Y. Jiang</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tfeng7.github.io/images/icon_hu9dc07378506dda20152aae5397c06783_79375_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Y. Jiang</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/y.-jiang/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reply to Comment by Michael K. Tippett on “On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.”</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-jgra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-jgra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tippett (2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD029345&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD029345&lt;/a&gt;) provides an insightful comment on the theoretical consideration part of Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002),&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002),&lt;/a&gt; which studied the relationship between probabilistic and deterministic skills in dynamical seasonal climate prediction. The author connects the theoretical finding of Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;) with some previous studies on this topic and further provide a simple‐form approximation to the derived theoretical relation in Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002)&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002)&lt;/a&gt;. However, the author also indicates the difference between the considerations in Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;) and the previous studies. In this reply, we present a detailed explanation to the readers of the difference between these considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang, D., X.-Q. Yang*, D. Ye, X. Sun, J. Fang, C. Chu, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Jiang, J. Liang, X. Ren, Y. Zhang, Y. Tang, 2019: Reply to Comment by Michael K. Tippett on “On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;124&lt;/strong&gt;, 3982–3983, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD030289&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD030289&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jgra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jgra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the gradually increasing emphasis on assessing the skill of dynamical seasonal climate predictions from the probabilistic perspective, there is a lack of in‐depth understanding that an inherent relationship may exist between the probabilistic and deterministic seasonal forecast skills. In this study, we focus on investigating this relationship, through theoretical consideration based on an analytical approach and diagnostic analysis of the historical forecasts produced by multiple dynamical models. The probabilistic forecast skill is gauged in terms of its two different attributes: resolution and reliability, while the deterministic forecast skill is measured in terms of anomaly correlation (AC). Through the theoretical consideration under certain simplified assumptions, a nonlinear, monotonic relationship is analytically derived between the resolution and the AC. Subsequent diagnostic analysis shows that the resolution and AC skills of both the multimodel ensemble and its member single models indeed appear to be approximately monotonically and nonlinearly related, specifically when they are calculated in a zonally aggregated manner by which the impact of finite sample size is reduced. This observed relationship has a specific form that is consistent with what the theory predicts. In short, the theoretical result is well verified by the dynamical model forecasts. Diagnostic analysis also shows that no good relationship exists between the reliability and the AC, signifying the difference of reliability and resolution in nature. A specific application of the proven resolution‐AC coherence is also demonstrated. The proved resolution‐AC relationship can facilitate comparisons among various assessments of seasonal climate prediction skill from the deterministic or probabilistic perspective alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang, D., X.-Q. Yang*, D. Ye, X. Sun, J. Fang, C. Chu, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Jiang, J. Liang, X. Ren, Y. Zhang, Y. Tang, 2018: On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;123&lt;/strong&gt;, 5261–5283, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the tropical Pacific and Indian Ocean warming since the late 1970s on wintertime Northern Hemispheric atmospheric circulation and East Asian climate interdecadal changes</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Observation reveals that the tropical Pacific-Indian Ocean (TPIO) has experienced a pronounced interdecadal warming since the end of the 1970s. Meanwhile, the wintertime midlatitude Northern Hemispheric atmospheric circulation and East Asian climate have also undergone substantial interdecadal changes. The effect of the TPIO warming on these interdecadal changes are identified by a suite of AMIP-type atmospheric general circulation model experiments in which the model is integrated from September 1948 to December 1999 with prescribed historical, observed realistic sea surface temperature (SST) in a specific region and climatological SST elsewhere. Results show that the TPIO warming reproduces quite well the observed Northern Hemispheric wintertime interdecadal changes, suggesting that these interdecadal changes primarily originate from the TPIO warming. However, each sub-region of TPIO has its own distinct contribution. Comparatively, the tropical central-eastern Pacific (TCEP) and tropical western Pacific (TWP) warming makes dominant contributions to the observed positive-phase PNA-like interdecadal anomaly over the North Pacific sector, while the tropical Indian Ocean (TIO) warming tends to cancel these contributions. Meanwhile, the TIO and TWP warming makes dominant contributions to the observed positive NAO-like interdecadal anomaly over the North Atlantic sector as well as the interdecadal anomalies over the Eurasian sector, although the TWP warming’s contribution is relatively small. These remote responses are directly attributed to the TPIO warming-induced tropical convection, rainfall and diabatic heating increases, in which the TIO warming has the most significant effect. Moreover, the TPIO warming excites a Gill-type pattern anomaly over the tropical western Pacific, with a low-level anticyclonic circulation anomaly over the Philippine Sea. Of three sub-regions, the TIO warming dominates such a pattern, although the TWP warming tends to cancel this effect. The anticyclonic circulation anomaly intensifies the southwesterly flow that transfers more moisture from the Bay of Bengal to East Asia and considerably increases the winter precipitation over the southern East Asia. This is strongly supported by the observational fact that there has been a significant interdecadal increase of winter precipitation over the southern China since the end of the 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chu, C., X.-Q. Yang*, X. Sun, D. Yang, Y. Jiang, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; and J. Liang, 2017: Effect of the tropical Pacific and Indian Ocean warming since the late 1970s on wintertime Northern Hemispheric atmospheric circulation and East Asian climate interdecadal changes. &lt;em&gt;Clim. Dyn.&lt;/em&gt;, doi:10.1007/s00382-017-3790-y. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00382-017-3790-y&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00382-017-3790-y&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
