<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>W. Zhou | Welcome</title>
    <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/w.-zhou/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tfeng7.github.io/author/w.-zhou/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>W. Zhou</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tfeng7.github.io/images/icon_hu9dc07378506dda20152aae5397c06783_79375_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>W. Zhou</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/w.-zhou/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synoptic-Scale Waves in Sheared Background Flow over the Western North Pacific</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-jas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-jas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tropical depression (TD)-type waves are the dominant mode of synoptic-scale ﬂuctuations over the western North Paciﬁc. By applying spatiotemporal ﬁlters to the observed OLR data and the NCEP–DOE AMIP-II reanalysis data for 1979–2013, this study reveals the characteristics and energetics of convectively coupled TD-type waves under the effects of different circulation patterns in association with vertical wind shear. Results exhibit that different ambient sheared ﬂows signiﬁcantly affect the vertical structure of westward-propagating TD-type waves, with a lower-tropospheric mode in an easterly sheared background and an upper-tropospheric mode in a westerly sheared background. Energetic diagnoses demonstrate that when the disturbance is trapped in the lower (upper) level by easterly (westerly) shear, the horizontal mean ﬂow in the lower (upper) level favors wave growth by converting energy from the shear of the zonal mean ﬂow (from the convergence of the meridional mean ﬂow). During the penetration of a westward-propagating synoptic-scale disturbance from a westerly sheared ﬂow into an easterly sheared ﬂow, the upper-level disturbance decays, and the lower-level disturbance intensiﬁes. Meanwhile, the upper-level kinetic energy is transferred downward, but the effect induces the wave growth only conﬁned to the midlevels. Consequently, the low-level growth of the westward-propagating upper-level synoptic-scale disturbance is mainly attributed to the barotropic conversion of horizontal mean ﬂow in the lower troposphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feng, T.&lt;/strong&gt;, X.-Q. Yang*, W. Zhou, R. Huang, L. Wu, and D. Yang, 2016: Synoptic-Scale Waves in Sheared Background Flow over the Western North Pacific. &lt;em&gt;J. Atmos. Sci.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;73&lt;/strong&gt;, 4583–4603, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-16-0064.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-16-0064.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
