<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>台风 | Welcome</title>
    <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/tag/%E5%8F%B0%E9%A3%8E/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tfeng7.github.io/tag/%E5%8F%B0%E9%A3%8E/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>台风</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tfeng7.github.io/images/icon_hu9dc07378506dda20152aae5397c06783_79375_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>台风</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/tag/%E5%8F%B0%E9%A3%8E/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of Tropical Cyclone Activity over the South China Sea: Local and Nonlocal Tropical Cyclones.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-tao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, J.-M. Chen, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2020: Characteristics of Tropical Cyclone Activity over the South China Sea: Local and Nonlocal Tropical Cyclones. &lt;em&gt;Terrestrial, Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt;, 261-271, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3319/TAO.2019.07.01.02&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3319/TAO.2019.07.01.02&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The upper ocean thermodynamic and biological responses to two sequential tropical cyclones (TCs) over the Northwestern Pacific Ocean were investigated using multi-satellite datasets, in situ observations and numerical model outputs. During Kalmaegi and Fung-Wong, three distinct cold patches were observed at sea surface. The locations of these cold patches are highly correlated with relatively shallower depth of the 26 °C isotherm and mixed layer depth (MLD) and lower upper ocean heat content. The enhancement of surface chlorophyll a (chl-a) concentration was detected in these three regions as well, mainly due to the TC-induced mixing and upwelling as well as the terrestrial runoff. Moreover, the pre-existing ocean cyclonic eddy (CE) has been found to significantly modulate the magnitude of surface cooling and chl-a increase. With the deepening of the MLD on the right side of TCs, the temperature of the mixed layer decreased and the salinity increased. The sequential TCs had superimposed effects on the upper ocean response. The possible causes of sudden track change in sequential TCs scenario were also explored. Both atmospheric and oceanic conditions play noticeable roles in abrupt northward turning of the subsequent TC Fung-Wong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ning, J., Q. Xu*, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, H. Zhang, T. Wang, 2019: Upper Ocean Response to Two Sequential Tropical Cyclones over the Northwestern Pacific Ocean. &lt;em&gt;Remote Sensing&lt;/em&gt;, 11, 2431, doi:10.3390/rs11202431.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-sces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-sces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2018 typhoon season in the western North Pacific (WNP) was highly active, with 26 named tropical cyclones (TCs) from June to November, which exceeded the climatological mean (22) and was the second busiest season over the past twenty years. More TCs formed in the eastern region of the WNP and the northern region of the South China Sea (SCS). More TCs took the northeast quadrant in the WNP, recurving from northwestward to northward and causing heavy damages in mainland China (69.73 billion yuan) in 2018. Multiscale climate variability is conducive to an active season via an enhanced monsoon trough and a weakened subtropical high in the WNP. The large-scale backgrounds in 2018 showed a favorable environment for TCs established by a developing central Pacific (CP) El Niño and positive Pacific meridional mode (PMM) episode on interannual timescales. The tropical central Pacific (TCP) SST forcing exhibits primary control on TCs in the WNP and large-scale circulations, which are insensitive to the PMM. During CP El Niño years, anomalous convection associated with the TCP warming leads to significantly increased anomalous cyclonic circulation in the WNP because of a Gill-type Rossby wave response. As a result, the weakened subtropical high and enhanced monsoon trough shift eastward and northward, which favor TC genesis and development. Although such increased TC activity in 2018 might be slightly suppressed by interdecadal climate variability, it was mostly attributed to the favorable interannual background. In addition, high-frequency climate signals, such as intraseasonal oscillations (ISOs) and synoptic-scale disturbances (SSDs), interacted with the enhanced monsoon trough and strongly modulated regional TC genesis and development in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;*, and Y. Tang, 2019: Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018. &lt;em&gt;Sci. China Earth Sci.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11430-019-9474-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11430-019-9474-4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causes of the active typhoon season in 2016 following a strong El Niño with a comparison to 1998</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-joc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-joc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article analysed two typhoon seasons (1998 and 2016) over the western North Pacific (WNP) with similar preceding background conditions of the tropical Pacific sea surface temperature (SST). Following the strong El Niño event in the preceding winter, the typhoon season was inactive in 1998 while active in 2016. Compared with 1998, the monsoon trough (MT) in 2016 shifted more eastwards, leading to an increase of the mid‐level water vapour, lower‐tropospheric relative vorticity and upper‐tropospheric divergence, and a decrease of the vertical wind shear. Additionally, the eastwards extension of the MT in 2016 induced more active tropical depression (TD)‐type waves than those in 1998. The analysis of the energy budget suggested that the eastwards shift of the MT during the 2016 typhoon season provided increased eddy kinetic energy for typhoon genesis, due to the joint contributions of the meridional shear of the mean zonal winds and the zonal wind convergence over the WNP. Moreover, the WNP entered a La Niña‐like SST pattern after July 2016. The relatively slower developing process of this pattern sustained the warmer SST anomalies and the anomalous cyclonic circulation, which the eastwards extension of the MT can be attributed. Hence, compared to 1998, the active typhoon season in 2016 is attributed to the eastwards extension of the MT, more active TD‐type wave activities, and slow developing process of a La Niña‐like SST pattern in 2016 typhoon season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huangfu, J.*, R. Huang, W. Chen, and &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018: Causes of the active typhoon season in 2016 following a strong El Niño with a comparison to 1998. &lt;em&gt;Int. J. Climatol&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt;, 1107–1118, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5437&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5437&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Two Types of El Niño on Tropical Cyclones over the Western North Pacific: Sensitivity to Location and Intensity of Pacific Warming</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present study investigates the impact of various central Pacific (CP) and eastern Pacific (EP) warming on tropical cyclones (TCs) over the western North Pacific (WNP) for the period 1948–2015 based on observational and reanalysis data. Four distinctly different forms of tropical Pacific warming are identified to examine different impacts of locations and intensity of tropical Pacific warming on the WNP TCs. It is shown that WNP TC activity related to ENSO shows stronger sensitivity to the intensity of CP SST warming. The locations of TC genesis in an extreme EP El Niño featuring concurrent strong CP and EP warming (CEPW) display a notable southeastward shift that is generally similar to the CP El Niño featuring CP warming alone (CPW). These influences are clearly different from the effects of moderate EP El Niño associated with EP warming alone (EPW). The above influences of Pacific warming on TCs possibly occur via atmospheric circulation variability. Anomalous convection associated with CP SST warming drives anomalous low-level westerlies away from the equator as a result of a Gill-type Rossby wave response, leading to an enhanced broad-zone, eastward-extending monsoon trough (MT). An anomalous Walker circulation in response to EP SST warming drives an increase in anomalous equatorial westerlies over the WNP, leading to a narrow-zone, slightly equatorward shift of the eastward-extending MT. These changes in the MT coincide with a shift in large-scale environments and synoptic-scale perturbations, which favor TC genesis and development. In addition, during weaker EP SST warming (WEPW) with similar intensity to CPW, local SST forcing exhibits primary control on WNP TCs and atmospheric circulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, J.-M. Chen, and &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018: Impact of Two Types of El Niño on Tropical Cyclones over the Western North Pacific: Sensitivity to Location and Intensity of Pacific Warming. &lt;em&gt;J. Climate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt;, 1725–1742, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-17-0298.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-17-0298.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the Interannual Variation of Cross-Equatorial Flow on Tropical Cyclogenesis Over the Western North Pacific</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-jtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-jtm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The influence of the interannual variation of cross-equatorial flow (CEF) on tropical cyclogenesis over the western North Pacific (WNP) is examined in this paper by using the tropical cyclone (TC) best track data from the Joint Typhoon Warning Center and the JRA-25 reanalysis dataset. The results showed that the number of TCs forming to the east of 140°E over the southeastern part of the western North Pacific (WNP) is in highly positive correlation with the variation of the CEF near 125°E and 150°E, i.e., the number of tropical cyclogeneses increases when the cross-equatorial flows are strong. Composite analyses showed that during the years of strong CEF, the variations of OLR, vertical wind shear between 200-850 hPa, 850 hPa relative vorticity and 200 hPa divergence are favorable for tropical cyclogenesis to the east of 140°E over the tropical WNP, and vice versa. Moreover, it is also discussed from the view of barotropic energy conversion that during the years of strong CEF, an eastward-extended monsoon trough leads to the rapid growth of eddy kinetic energy over the eastern part of WNP, which is favorable for tropical cyclogenesis; but during the years of weak CEF, the monsoon trough is located westward in the western part of the WNP, consistent with the growth area of eddy kinetic energy. As a result, there are fewer TC geneses over the eastern part of WNP. Besides, the abrupt strengthening of a close-by CEF 2-4 days before tropical cyclogenesis may be the one of its triggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feng, T.&lt;/strong&gt;*, X. Shen, R. Huang, and G. Chen, 2017: Influence of the Interannual Variation of Cross-Equatorial Flow on Tropical Cyclogenesis Over the Western North Pacific. &lt;em&gt;J. Trop. Meteorol.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt;, 68–80, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.16555/j.1006-8775.2017.01.007&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.16555/j.1006-8775.2017.01.007&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdecadal variation of tropical cyclone genesis and its relationship to the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-ijc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-ijc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using the European Centre for Medium‐Range Weather Forecasts Interim Reanalysis data set and the tropical cyclone (TC) best track data obtained from the International Best Tracks Archive for Climate Stewardship project from June to November for the epoch of 1979–2013, this study reexamines the recent interdecadal shift in TC genesis over the western North Pacific (WNP) in the late 1990s. An interdecadal decrease in the frequency of the WNP TC genesis was observed during 1998–2013 compared to the period of 1979–1997. The spatial distribution of the interdecadal decrease of the WNP TC genesis running northwest‐southeast, consistent with the monsoon trough (MT) zone. The results imply that the WNP genesis may be closely related to the MT on the interdecadal timescale. After the late 1990s, the intensity of the WNP MT becomes weaker and it extends more westward, thereby providing an unfavourable condition for the TC genesis. Through a diagnosis of the energetics, we suggested that the barotropic energy conversion in the eastern part of the WNP MT tends to be weakened in the late 1990s, hence less energy to support the WNP TC genesis. Both the meridional shear and the convergence of the mean zonal winds over the eastern WNP MT have an important impact on the conversion from mean kinetic energy to eddy kinetic energy, which can be considered as the atmospheric cause of the interdecadal decrease of TC genesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huangfu, J.*, R. Huang, W. Chen, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; and L. Wu, 2017: Interdecadal variation of tropical cyclone genesis and its relationship to the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific. International Journal of Climatology, 37, 3587–3596, doi:10.1002/joc.4939.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> 关于西北太平洋季风槽年际和年代际变异及其对热带气旋生成影响和机理的研究</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-rdqx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-rdqx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;总结和综述近年来中国科学院大气物理研究所季风系统研究中心，关于西北太平洋季风槽的年际和年代际变异及其对热带气旋和台风（TCs）生成的影响和机理的气候学研究进展，并综述一些有关的国内外研究。给出了夏、秋季西北太平洋季风槽的气候特征以及利于TCs生成的四类季风槽环流型，表明了西北太平洋季风槽强度和位置有明显的年际和年代际变异。特别是揭示了西北太平洋季风槽的年际和年代际变异不仅通过影响西北太平洋上空对流层低层气流的涡度和对流层高层的散度、对流层中、下层的水汽以及对流层上下层风场的垂直切变等利于TCs生成的大尺度环境因子的分布而影响TCs的生成，而且通过对热带对流耦合波动的转化和提供扰动能量而对TCs生成起着重要的动力作用。还指出今后有关西北太平洋季风槽和TCs活动一些亟需进一步研究的气候学问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;黄荣辉*,皇甫静亮,武亮,&lt;strong&gt;冯涛&lt;/strong&gt;,陈光华, 2016, 关于西北太平洋季风槽年际和年代际变异及其对热带气旋生成影响和机理的研究,热带气象学报，32(6):767-785&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale circulation patterns favourable to tropical cyclogenesis over the western North Pacific and associated barotropic energy conversions</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2014-joc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2014-joc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Feng, T.&lt;/strong&gt;*, G. H. Chen, R. H. Huang, and X. Y. Shen, 2014: Large-scale circulation patterns favourable to tropical cyclogenesis over the western North Pacific and associated barotropic energy conversions. &lt;em&gt;Int. J. Climatol&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;34&lt;/strong&gt;, 216–227, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.3680&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.3680&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>近年来关于西北太平洋热带气旋和台风活动的气候学研究进展</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2013-dqkx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2013-dqkx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;本文主要综述和回顾了近年来季风系统研究中心关于西北太平洋热带气旋和台风(TCs)活动的气候学研究进展及有关的国内外研究。文中不仅回顾了最近关于夏、秋季西北太平洋利于TCs生成的大尺度环流型及其与涡旋的正压能量交换、西北太平洋TCs活动的年际和年代际及季节内的变化特征、以及今后全球变暖背景下西北太平洋TCs活动的变化趋势的气候学研究进展,而且综述了西北太平洋季风槽及热带对流耦合波动对西北太平洋上TCs生成的动力作用的研究。此外,文中还指出今后有关西北太平洋TCs活动一些亟需进一步研究的气候学问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;冯涛&lt;/strong&gt;, 黄荣辉, 陈光华, 武亮, 黄平, 王磊, 2013: 近年来关于西北太平洋热带气旋和台风活动的气候学研究进展. 大气科学, &lt;strong&gt;37,&lt;/strong&gt; 364-382.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
