<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>W. Chen | Welcome</title>
    <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/w.-chen/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tfeng7.github.io/author/w.-chen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>W. Chen</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tfeng7.github.io/images/icon_hu9dc07378506dda20152aae5397c06783_79375_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>W. Chen</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/w.-chen/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causes of the active typhoon season in 2016 following a strong El Niño with a comparison to 1998</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-joc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-joc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article analysed two typhoon seasons (1998 and 2016) over the western North Pacific (WNP) with similar preceding background conditions of the tropical Pacific sea surface temperature (SST). Following the strong El Niño event in the preceding winter, the typhoon season was inactive in 1998 while active in 2016. Compared with 1998, the monsoon trough (MT) in 2016 shifted more eastwards, leading to an increase of the mid‐level water vapour, lower‐tropospheric relative vorticity and upper‐tropospheric divergence, and a decrease of the vertical wind shear. Additionally, the eastwards extension of the MT in 2016 induced more active tropical depression (TD)‐type waves than those in 1998. The analysis of the energy budget suggested that the eastwards shift of the MT during the 2016 typhoon season provided increased eddy kinetic energy for typhoon genesis, due to the joint contributions of the meridional shear of the mean zonal winds and the zonal wind convergence over the WNP. Moreover, the WNP entered a La Niña‐like SST pattern after July 2016. The relatively slower developing process of this pattern sustained the warmer SST anomalies and the anomalous cyclonic circulation, which the eastwards extension of the MT can be attributed. Hence, compared to 1998, the active typhoon season in 2016 is attributed to the eastwards extension of the MT, more active TD‐type wave activities, and slow developing process of a La Niña‐like SST pattern in 2016 typhoon season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huangfu, J.*, R. Huang, W. Chen, and &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018: Causes of the active typhoon season in 2016 following a strong El Niño with a comparison to 1998. &lt;em&gt;Int. J. Climatol&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt;, 1107–1118, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5437&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5437&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdecadal variation of tropical cyclone genesis and its relationship to the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-ijc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-ijc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using the European Centre for Medium‐Range Weather Forecasts Interim Reanalysis data set and the tropical cyclone (TC) best track data obtained from the International Best Tracks Archive for Climate Stewardship project from June to November for the epoch of 1979–2013, this study reexamines the recent interdecadal shift in TC genesis over the western North Pacific (WNP) in the late 1990s. An interdecadal decrease in the frequency of the WNP TC genesis was observed during 1998–2013 compared to the period of 1979–1997. The spatial distribution of the interdecadal decrease of the WNP TC genesis running northwest‐southeast, consistent with the monsoon trough (MT) zone. The results imply that the WNP genesis may be closely related to the MT on the interdecadal timescale. After the late 1990s, the intensity of the WNP MT becomes weaker and it extends more westward, thereby providing an unfavourable condition for the TC genesis. Through a diagnosis of the energetics, we suggested that the barotropic energy conversion in the eastern part of the WNP MT tends to be weakened in the late 1990s, hence less energy to support the WNP TC genesis. Both the meridional shear and the convergence of the mean zonal winds over the eastern WNP MT have an important impact on the conversion from mean kinetic energy to eddy kinetic energy, which can be considered as the atmospheric cause of the interdecadal decrease of TC genesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huangfu, J.*, R. Huang, W. Chen, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; and L. Wu, 2017: Interdecadal variation of tropical cyclone genesis and its relationship to the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific. International Journal of Climatology, 37, 3587–3596, doi:10.1002/joc.4939.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
