<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications | Welcome</title>
    <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publications</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tfeng7.github.io/images/icon_hu9dc07378506dda20152aae5397c06783_79375_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reexamination of the climatology and variability of the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific using a daily index</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-jc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-jc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This study developed a daily index to represent the northwest Pacific monsoon trough using westerly related cyclonic vorticity after removing tropical cyclones (TCs) from the reanalysis dataset. This index sufficiently captures the spatial and temporal variations in the monsoon trough. The use of this daily index revealed new features in the monsoon trough, including daily statistical characteristics, the active period over a year, and the main periodicity. A monsoon trough can be identified as active when the daily index is greater than $2.0×10^{-4} s^{-1}$. Active monsoon troughs occur during half of the summertime, and these is no monsoon trough on one-third of days, with the remaining days categorized as inactive. The most active month is August, in which approximately twenty days exhibit an active monsoon trough. Using this index, an active monsoon trough period, which is related to vigorous TC activity, was determined by identifying the establishment and decay dates for each year from 1979 to 2016. During most years, the active monsoon trough is established in mid-July and decays in late October, persisting for three to five months during the boreal summer. Moreover, spectral and wavelet analyses demonstrated the presence of intraseasonal, interannual and interdecadal variabilities in the monsoon trough. The dominant periodicity for the interannual variability varied from 1.5 to 4 years in different decades.The relationship between the monsoon trough and TCs are also revealed using this index, that approximately 60% of TC formations were related to an active monsoon trough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feng T.&lt;/strong&gt;*, X.-Q. Yang, X. Sun, D. Yang, C. Chu, 2020. Reexamination of the climatology and variability of the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific using a daily trough index.  &lt;em&gt;Journal of Climate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-19-0459.1.5&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-19-0459.1.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do the Monsoon Trough and the Tropical Upper-Tropospheric Trough Affect Synoptic-Scale Waves: A Comparative Study</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-jmsj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-jmsj/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using the Climate Forecast System Reanalysis, Joint Typhoon Warning Center best track, and Tropical Rainfall Measuring Mission precipitation data, two long-lasting synoptic-scale wave trains in 2004 and 2006 are selected to investigate the atmospheric factors controlling the structures of westward-propagating synoptic-scale disturbances over the tropical western North Pacific. The essential difference between these two wave trains is found in their vertical structures. In 2004, the maximum perturbations occurred from the middle to lower troposphere with an equivalent barotropic structure; however, in 2006, they primarily occurred in the upper troposphere with a prominent tilt regarding height. Distinct configurations of the monsoon troughs, the tropical upper-tropospheric troughs (TUTT), and associated vertical wind shear caused such structural differences. In 2004, the TUTT shifted eastward, creating an easterly sheared environment to confine synoptic-scale waves in the lower troposphere. Then, the monsoon trough enhanced the wave activity through barotropic energy conversion in the lower troposphere. In contrast, while the TUTT shifted westward in 2006, synoptic-scale waves prevailed in the upper troposphere by the environmental westerly shear. Meanwhile, the disturbances developed in the upper troposphere through to the conversion of kinetic energy from the TUTT, exhibiting a top-heavy vertical structure. The coherent movement of the monsoon trough and the TUTT modulate the vertical structure and the development of the synoptic-scale waves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feng T.&lt;/strong&gt;, X.-Q. Yang, R. Huang, L. Wu*, D. Yang, 2020. How Do the Monsoon Trough and the Tropical Upper-Tropospheric Trough Affect Synoptic-Scale Waves: A Comparative Study. *Journal of the Meteorological society of Japan*, **98**, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.2151/jmsj.2020-037&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.2151/jmsj.2020-037&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of Tropical Cyclone Activity over the South China Sea: Local and Nonlocal Tropical Cyclones.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-tao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, J.-M. Chen, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2020: Characteristics of Tropical Cyclone Activity over the South China Sea: Local and Nonlocal Tropical Cyclones. &lt;em&gt;Terrestrial, Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt;, 261-271, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3319/TAO.2019.07.01.02&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3319/TAO.2019.07.01.02&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The upper ocean thermodynamic and biological responses to two sequential tropical cyclones (TCs) over the Northwestern Pacific Ocean were investigated using multi-satellite datasets, in situ observations and numerical model outputs. During Kalmaegi and Fung-Wong, three distinct cold patches were observed at sea surface. The locations of these cold patches are highly correlated with relatively shallower depth of the 26 °C isotherm and mixed layer depth (MLD) and lower upper ocean heat content. The enhancement of surface chlorophyll a (chl-a) concentration was detected in these three regions as well, mainly due to the TC-induced mixing and upwelling as well as the terrestrial runoff. Moreover, the pre-existing ocean cyclonic eddy (CE) has been found to significantly modulate the magnitude of surface cooling and chl-a increase. With the deepening of the MLD on the right side of TCs, the temperature of the mixed layer decreased and the salinity increased. The sequential TCs had superimposed effects on the upper ocean response. The possible causes of sudden track change in sequential TCs scenario were also explored. Both atmospheric and oceanic conditions play noticeable roles in abrupt northward turning of the subsequent TC Fung-Wong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ning, J., Q. Xu*, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, H. Zhang, T. Wang, 2019: Upper Ocean Response to Two Sequential Tropical Cyclones over the Northwestern Pacific Ocean. &lt;em&gt;Remote Sensing&lt;/em&gt;, 11, 2431, doi:10.3390/rs11202431.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-sces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-sces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2018 typhoon season in the western North Pacific (WNP) was highly active, with 26 named tropical cyclones (TCs) from June to November, which exceeded the climatological mean (22) and was the second busiest season over the past twenty years. More TCs formed in the eastern region of the WNP and the northern region of the South China Sea (SCS). More TCs took the northeast quadrant in the WNP, recurving from northwestward to northward and causing heavy damages in mainland China (69.73 billion yuan) in 2018. Multiscale climate variability is conducive to an active season via an enhanced monsoon trough and a weakened subtropical high in the WNP. The large-scale backgrounds in 2018 showed a favorable environment for TCs established by a developing central Pacific (CP) El Niño and positive Pacific meridional mode (PMM) episode on interannual timescales. The tropical central Pacific (TCP) SST forcing exhibits primary control on TCs in the WNP and large-scale circulations, which are insensitive to the PMM. During CP El Niño years, anomalous convection associated with the TCP warming leads to significantly increased anomalous cyclonic circulation in the WNP because of a Gill-type Rossby wave response. As a result, the weakened subtropical high and enhanced monsoon trough shift eastward and northward, which favor TC genesis and development. Although such increased TC activity in 2018 might be slightly suppressed by interdecadal climate variability, it was mostly attributed to the favorable interannual background. In addition, high-frequency climate signals, such as intraseasonal oscillations (ISOs) and synoptic-scale disturbances (SSDs), interacted with the enhanced monsoon trough and strongly modulated regional TC genesis and development in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;*, and Y. Tang, 2019: Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018. &lt;em&gt;Sci. China Earth Sci.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11430-019-9474-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11430-019-9474-4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reply to Comment by Michael K. Tippett on “On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.”</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-jgra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-jgra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tippett (2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD029345&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD029345&lt;/a&gt;) provides an insightful comment on the theoretical consideration part of Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002),&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002),&lt;/a&gt; which studied the relationship between probabilistic and deterministic skills in dynamical seasonal climate prediction. The author connects the theoretical finding of Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;) with some previous studies on this topic and further provide a simple‐form approximation to the derived theoretical relation in Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002)&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002)&lt;/a&gt;. However, the author also indicates the difference between the considerations in Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;) and the previous studies. In this reply, we present a detailed explanation to the readers of the difference between these considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang, D., X.-Q. Yang*, D. Ye, X. Sun, J. Fang, C. Chu, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Jiang, J. Liang, X. Ren, Y. Zhang, Y. Tang, 2019: Reply to Comment by Michael K. Tippett on “On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;124&lt;/strong&gt;, 3982–3983, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD030289&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD030289&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causes of the active typhoon season in 2016 following a strong El Niño with a comparison to 1998</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-joc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-joc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article analysed two typhoon seasons (1998 and 2016) over the western North Pacific (WNP) with similar preceding background conditions of the tropical Pacific sea surface temperature (SST). Following the strong El Niño event in the preceding winter, the typhoon season was inactive in 1998 while active in 2016. Compared with 1998, the monsoon trough (MT) in 2016 shifted more eastwards, leading to an increase of the mid‐level water vapour, lower‐tropospheric relative vorticity and upper‐tropospheric divergence, and a decrease of the vertical wind shear. Additionally, the eastwards extension of the MT in 2016 induced more active tropical depression (TD)‐type waves than those in 1998. The analysis of the energy budget suggested that the eastwards shift of the MT during the 2016 typhoon season provided increased eddy kinetic energy for typhoon genesis, due to the joint contributions of the meridional shear of the mean zonal winds and the zonal wind convergence over the WNP. Moreover, the WNP entered a La Niña‐like SST pattern after July 2016. The relatively slower developing process of this pattern sustained the warmer SST anomalies and the anomalous cyclonic circulation, which the eastwards extension of the MT can be attributed. Hence, compared to 1998, the active typhoon season in 2016 is attributed to the eastwards extension of the MT, more active TD‐type wave activities, and slow developing process of a La Niña‐like SST pattern in 2016 typhoon season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huangfu, J.*, R. Huang, W. Chen, and &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018: Causes of the active typhoon season in 2016 following a strong El Niño with a comparison to 1998. &lt;em&gt;Int. J. Climatol&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt;, 1107–1118, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5437&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5437&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Two Types of El Niño on Tropical Cyclones over the Western North Pacific: Sensitivity to Location and Intensity of Pacific Warming</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present study investigates the impact of various central Pacific (CP) and eastern Pacific (EP) warming on tropical cyclones (TCs) over the western North Pacific (WNP) for the period 1948–2015 based on observational and reanalysis data. Four distinctly different forms of tropical Pacific warming are identified to examine different impacts of locations and intensity of tropical Pacific warming on the WNP TCs. It is shown that WNP TC activity related to ENSO shows stronger sensitivity to the intensity of CP SST warming. The locations of TC genesis in an extreme EP El Niño featuring concurrent strong CP and EP warming (CEPW) display a notable southeastward shift that is generally similar to the CP El Niño featuring CP warming alone (CPW). These influences are clearly different from the effects of moderate EP El Niño associated with EP warming alone (EPW). The above influences of Pacific warming on TCs possibly occur via atmospheric circulation variability. Anomalous convection associated with CP SST warming drives anomalous low-level westerlies away from the equator as a result of a Gill-type Rossby wave response, leading to an enhanced broad-zone, eastward-extending monsoon trough (MT). An anomalous Walker circulation in response to EP SST warming drives an increase in anomalous equatorial westerlies over the WNP, leading to a narrow-zone, slightly equatorward shift of the eastward-extending MT. These changes in the MT coincide with a shift in large-scale environments and synoptic-scale perturbations, which favor TC genesis and development. In addition, during weaker EP SST warming (WEPW) with similar intensity to CPW, local SST forcing exhibits primary control on WNP TCs and atmospheric circulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, J.-M. Chen, and &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018: Impact of Two Types of El Niño on Tropical Cyclones over the Western North Pacific: Sensitivity to Location and Intensity of Pacific Warming. &lt;em&gt;J. Climate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt;, 1725–1742, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-17-0298.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-17-0298.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jgra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jgra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the gradually increasing emphasis on assessing the skill of dynamical seasonal climate predictions from the probabilistic perspective, there is a lack of in‐depth understanding that an inherent relationship may exist between the probabilistic and deterministic seasonal forecast skills. In this study, we focus on investigating this relationship, through theoretical consideration based on an analytical approach and diagnostic analysis of the historical forecasts produced by multiple dynamical models. The probabilistic forecast skill is gauged in terms of its two different attributes: resolution and reliability, while the deterministic forecast skill is measured in terms of anomaly correlation (AC). Through the theoretical consideration under certain simplified assumptions, a nonlinear, monotonic relationship is analytically derived between the resolution and the AC. Subsequent diagnostic analysis shows that the resolution and AC skills of both the multimodel ensemble and its member single models indeed appear to be approximately monotonically and nonlinearly related, specifically when they are calculated in a zonally aggregated manner by which the impact of finite sample size is reduced. This observed relationship has a specific form that is consistent with what the theory predicts. In short, the theoretical result is well verified by the dynamical model forecasts. Diagnostic analysis also shows that no good relationship exists between the reliability and the AC, signifying the difference of reliability and resolution in nature. A specific application of the proven resolution‐AC coherence is also demonstrated. The proved resolution‐AC relationship can facilitate comparisons among various assessments of seasonal climate prediction skill from the deterministic or probabilistic perspective alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang, D., X.-Q. Yang*, D. Ye, X. Sun, J. Fang, C. Chu, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Jiang, J. Liang, X. Ren, Y. Zhang, Y. Tang, 2018: On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;123&lt;/strong&gt;, 5261–5283, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the tropical Pacific and Indian Ocean warming since the late 1970s on wintertime Northern Hemispheric atmospheric circulation and East Asian climate interdecadal changes</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Observation reveals that the tropical Pacific-Indian Ocean (TPIO) has experienced a pronounced interdecadal warming since the end of the 1970s. Meanwhile, the wintertime midlatitude Northern Hemispheric atmospheric circulation and East Asian climate have also undergone substantial interdecadal changes. The effect of the TPIO warming on these interdecadal changes are identified by a suite of AMIP-type atmospheric general circulation model experiments in which the model is integrated from September 1948 to December 1999 with prescribed historical, observed realistic sea surface temperature (SST) in a specific region and climatological SST elsewhere. Results show that the TPIO warming reproduces quite well the observed Northern Hemispheric wintertime interdecadal changes, suggesting that these interdecadal changes primarily originate from the TPIO warming. However, each sub-region of TPIO has its own distinct contribution. Comparatively, the tropical central-eastern Pacific (TCEP) and tropical western Pacific (TWP) warming makes dominant contributions to the observed positive-phase PNA-like interdecadal anomaly over the North Pacific sector, while the tropical Indian Ocean (TIO) warming tends to cancel these contributions. Meanwhile, the TIO and TWP warming makes dominant contributions to the observed positive NAO-like interdecadal anomaly over the North Atlantic sector as well as the interdecadal anomalies over the Eurasian sector, although the TWP warming’s contribution is relatively small. These remote responses are directly attributed to the TPIO warming-induced tropical convection, rainfall and diabatic heating increases, in which the TIO warming has the most significant effect. Moreover, the TPIO warming excites a Gill-type pattern anomaly over the tropical western Pacific, with a low-level anticyclonic circulation anomaly over the Philippine Sea. Of three sub-regions, the TIO warming dominates such a pattern, although the TWP warming tends to cancel this effect. The anticyclonic circulation anomaly intensifies the southwesterly flow that transfers more moisture from the Bay of Bengal to East Asia and considerably increases the winter precipitation over the southern East Asia. This is strongly supported by the observational fact that there has been a significant interdecadal increase of winter precipitation over the southern China since the end of the 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chu, C., X.-Q. Yang*, X. Sun, D. Yang, Y. Jiang, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; and J. Liang, 2017: Effect of the tropical Pacific and Indian Ocean warming since the late 1970s on wintertime Northern Hemispheric atmospheric circulation and East Asian climate interdecadal changes. &lt;em&gt;Clim. Dyn.&lt;/em&gt;, doi:10.1007/s00382-017-3790-y. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00382-017-3790-y&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00382-017-3790-y&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of the Interannual Variation of Cross-Equatorial Flow on Tropical Cyclogenesis Over the Western North Pacific</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-jtm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-jtm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The influence of the interannual variation of cross-equatorial flow (CEF) on tropical cyclogenesis over the western North Pacific (WNP) is examined in this paper by using the tropical cyclone (TC) best track data from the Joint Typhoon Warning Center and the JRA-25 reanalysis dataset. The results showed that the number of TCs forming to the east of 140°E over the southeastern part of the western North Pacific (WNP) is in highly positive correlation with the variation of the CEF near 125°E and 150°E, i.e., the number of tropical cyclogeneses increases when the cross-equatorial flows are strong. Composite analyses showed that during the years of strong CEF, the variations of OLR, vertical wind shear between 200-850 hPa, 850 hPa relative vorticity and 200 hPa divergence are favorable for tropical cyclogenesis to the east of 140°E over the tropical WNP, and vice versa. Moreover, it is also discussed from the view of barotropic energy conversion that during the years of strong CEF, an eastward-extended monsoon trough leads to the rapid growth of eddy kinetic energy over the eastern part of WNP, which is favorable for tropical cyclogenesis; but during the years of weak CEF, the monsoon trough is located westward in the western part of the WNP, consistent with the growth area of eddy kinetic energy. As a result, there are fewer TC geneses over the eastern part of WNP. Besides, the abrupt strengthening of a close-by CEF 2-4 days before tropical cyclogenesis may be the one of its triggers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feng, T.&lt;/strong&gt;*, X. Shen, R. Huang, and G. Chen, 2017: Influence of the Interannual Variation of Cross-Equatorial Flow on Tropical Cyclogenesis Over the Western North Pacific. &lt;em&gt;J. Trop. Meteorol.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt;, 68–80, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.16555/j.1006-8775.2017.01.007&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.16555/j.1006-8775.2017.01.007&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdecadal variation of tropical cyclone genesis and its relationship to the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-ijc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-ijc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using the European Centre for Medium‐Range Weather Forecasts Interim Reanalysis data set and the tropical cyclone (TC) best track data obtained from the International Best Tracks Archive for Climate Stewardship project from June to November for the epoch of 1979–2013, this study reexamines the recent interdecadal shift in TC genesis over the western North Pacific (WNP) in the late 1990s. An interdecadal decrease in the frequency of the WNP TC genesis was observed during 1998–2013 compared to the period of 1979–1997. The spatial distribution of the interdecadal decrease of the WNP TC genesis running northwest‐southeast, consistent with the monsoon trough (MT) zone. The results imply that the WNP genesis may be closely related to the MT on the interdecadal timescale. After the late 1990s, the intensity of the WNP MT becomes weaker and it extends more westward, thereby providing an unfavourable condition for the TC genesis. Through a diagnosis of the energetics, we suggested that the barotropic energy conversion in the eastern part of the WNP MT tends to be weakened in the late 1990s, hence less energy to support the WNP TC genesis. Both the meridional shear and the convergence of the mean zonal winds over the eastern WNP MT have an important impact on the conversion from mean kinetic energy to eddy kinetic energy, which can be considered as the atmospheric cause of the interdecadal decrease of TC genesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huangfu, J.*, R. Huang, W. Chen, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; and L. Wu, 2017: Interdecadal variation of tropical cyclone genesis and its relationship to the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific. International Journal of Climatology, 37, 3587–3596, doi:10.1002/joc.4939.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> 关于西北太平洋季风槽年际和年代际变异及其对热带气旋生成影响和机理的研究</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-rdqx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-rdqx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;总结和综述近年来中国科学院大气物理研究所季风系统研究中心，关于西北太平洋季风槽的年际和年代际变异及其对热带气旋和台风（TCs）生成的影响和机理的气候学研究进展，并综述一些有关的国内外研究。给出了夏、秋季西北太平洋季风槽的气候特征以及利于TCs生成的四类季风槽环流型，表明了西北太平洋季风槽强度和位置有明显的年际和年代际变异。特别是揭示了西北太平洋季风槽的年际和年代际变异不仅通过影响西北太平洋上空对流层低层气流的涡度和对流层高层的散度、对流层中、下层的水汽以及对流层上下层风场的垂直切变等利于TCs生成的大尺度环境因子的分布而影响TCs的生成，而且通过对热带对流耦合波动的转化和提供扰动能量而对TCs生成起着重要的动力作用。还指出今后有关西北太平洋季风槽和TCs活动一些亟需进一步研究的气候学问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;黄荣辉*,皇甫静亮,武亮,&lt;strong&gt;冯涛&lt;/strong&gt;,陈光华, 2016, 关于西北太平洋季风槽年际和年代际变异及其对热带气旋生成影响和机理的研究,热带气象学报，32(6):767-785&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2004年与2006年7~9月西北太平洋上空大尺度环流场与天气尺度波动的差别及其对热带气旋生成的影响</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-dqkx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-dqkx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2004年和2006年是西北太平洋热带气旋(TC)活动具有明显差别的两年,2004年TC的生成位置主要位于西北太平洋的中东部上空,而2006年的TC主要生成在西北太平洋西部与中国南海.本文利用JTWC(Joint Typhoon Warning Center)热带气旋最佳路径数据、NCEP-DOE AMIP-II再分析资料和NOAA的OLR资料分析并比较了2004年与2006年7~9月西北太平洋上空大尺度环境要素场及天气尺度波动对TC生成的作用.分析结果表明:2004年7~9月与2006年7~9月西北太平洋上空季风槽的平均位置没有明显的区别,但是形态有着显著的差异.2004年季风槽的槽线不明显,在西北太平洋中部呈现一显著的气旋式环流;而2006年季风槽的槽线非常明显,槽线南北两侧呈现平直的水平气流,具有明显的水平切变特征.2004年和2006年对流层低层的相对涡度、高层辐散和垂直风切变具有明显的纬向分布差异,这是这两年TC生成的位置具有明显差异的重要原因之 一.并且,本文还分析对比了2004年以及2006年7~9月西北太平洋上空3~8 d周期的天气尺度波动的活 动,其结果表明:2004年和2006年TC的生成大多数与天气尺度波列的活动有关.2004年的天气尺度波列强度比较强,其活动的位置位于西北太平洋中、东侧上空;而2006年西北太平洋上空的天气尺度波列相对较弱,主要活动于中国南海和西北太平洋西部.纬向基本气流的切变与辐合所引起的瞬变扰动动能倾向的水平分布差异是天气尺度波动活动具有以上差异的重要原因.因此,西北太平洋大尺度环境场与天气尺度波动活动的区别共同造成了2004年7~9月的TC生成位置偏东、而2006年7~9月TC的生成位置偏西.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;冯涛&lt;/strong&gt;*, 黄荣辉, 杨修群, 沈新勇, 胡开明, 2016: 2004年与2006年7~9月西北太平洋上空大尺度环流场与天气尺度波动的差别及其对热带气旋生成的影响. 大气科学. 40(1): 157-175. DOI:10.3878/j.issn.1006-9895.1505.14162.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synoptic-Scale Waves in Sheared Background Flow over the Western North Pacific</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-jas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-jas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tropical depression (TD)-type waves are the dominant mode of synoptic-scale ﬂuctuations over the western North Paciﬁc. By applying spatiotemporal ﬁlters to the observed OLR data and the NCEP–DOE AMIP-II reanalysis data for 1979–2013, this study reveals the characteristics and energetics of convectively coupled TD-type waves under the effects of different circulation patterns in association with vertical wind shear. Results exhibit that different ambient sheared ﬂows signiﬁcantly affect the vertical structure of westward-propagating TD-type waves, with a lower-tropospheric mode in an easterly sheared background and an upper-tropospheric mode in a westerly sheared background. Energetic diagnoses demonstrate that when the disturbance is trapped in the lower (upper) level by easterly (westerly) shear, the horizontal mean ﬂow in the lower (upper) level favors wave growth by converting energy from the shear of the zonal mean ﬂow (from the convergence of the meridional mean ﬂow). During the penetration of a westward-propagating synoptic-scale disturbance from a westerly sheared ﬂow into an easterly sheared ﬂow, the upper-level disturbance decays, and the lower-level disturbance intensiﬁes. Meanwhile, the upper-level kinetic energy is transferred downward, but the effect induces the wave growth only conﬁned to the midlevels. Consequently, the low-level growth of the westward-propagating upper-level synoptic-scale disturbance is mainly attributed to the barotropic conversion of horizontal mean ﬂow in the lower troposphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feng, T.&lt;/strong&gt;, X.-Q. Yang*, W. Zhou, R. Huang, L. Wu, and D. Yang, 2016: Synoptic-Scale Waves in Sheared Background Flow over the Western North Pacific. &lt;em&gt;J. Atmos. Sci.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;73&lt;/strong&gt;, 4583–4603, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-16-0064.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JAS-D-16-0064.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>关于西太平洋暖池对西北太平洋季风槽和台风活动影响过程及其机理的最近研究进展</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-dqkx-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2016-dqkx-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;本文回顾和综述了近年来关于西太平洋暖池对西北太平洋热带气旋和台风（TCs）活动影响过程及其机理的研究进展。文中首先简单回顾了近年来关于西太平洋暖池热状态和菲律宾周围对流活动变化特征及其对与TCs活动有关的南海夏季风爆发和西太平洋副热带高压的季节内、年际变异的影响过程和机理的研究；然后，本文系统地回顾了近年来关于西太平洋暖池热状态通过西北太平洋季风槽影响TCs活动年际和年代际变化的影响过程及其机理的研究。此外，文中还指出了关于西太平洋暖池对西北太平洋上空季风槽和TCs活动变异的热力和动力作用需进一步深入研究的科学问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;黄荣辉*,皇甫静亮,刘永,&lt;strong&gt;冯涛&lt;/strong&gt;,武亮,陈际龙,王磊.2016.关于西太平洋暖池对西北太平洋季风槽和台风活动影响过程及其机理的最近研究进展[J].大气科学, doi:10.3878/j.issn.1006-9895.1512.15251.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20世纪90年代末东亚冬季风年代际变化特征及其内动力成因</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2014-dqkx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2014-dqkx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;黄荣辉, 刘永, 皇甫静亮, &lt;strong&gt;冯涛&lt;/strong&gt;, 2014: 20世纪90年代末东亚冬季风年代际变化特征及其内动力成因. 大气科学, &lt;strong&gt;38,&lt;/strong&gt; 627-644.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale circulation patterns favourable to tropical cyclogenesis over the western North Pacific and associated barotropic energy conversions</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2014-joc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2014-joc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Feng, T.&lt;/strong&gt;*, G. H. Chen, R. H. Huang, and X. Y. Shen, 2014: Large-scale circulation patterns favourable to tropical cyclogenesis over the western North Pacific and associated barotropic energy conversions. &lt;em&gt;Int. J. Climatol&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;34&lt;/strong&gt;, 216–227, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.3680&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.3680&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 世纪 90 年代末中国东部夏季降水和环流的年代际变化特征及其内动力成因</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2013-kxtb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2013-kxtb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;黄荣辉, 刘永,  &lt;strong&gt;冯涛&lt;/strong&gt;, 2013: 20 世纪 90 年代末中国东部夏季降水和环流的年代际变化特征及其内动力成因. 科学通报, &lt;strong&gt;58,&lt;/strong&gt; 617-628.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdecadal change of summer precipitation over Eastern China around the late-1990s and associated circulation anomalies, internal dynamical causes</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2013-csb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2013-csb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Huang, R., Y. Liu,  &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; 2013: Interdecadal change of summer precipitation over Eastern China around the late-1990s and associated circulation anomalies, internal dynamical causes. &lt;em&gt;Chin. Sci. Bull.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;58,&lt;/strong&gt; 1339-1349.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdecadal change of summer precipitation over Eastern China around the late-1990s and associated circulation anomalies, internal dynamical causes.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2014-rdqx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2014-rdqx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Huang, R., Y. Liu,  &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; 2013: Interdecadal change of summer precipitation over Eastern China around the late-1990s and associated circulation anomalies, internal dynamical causes. &lt;em&gt;Chin. Sci. Bull.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;58,&lt;/strong&gt; 1339-1349.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>近年来关于西北太平洋热带气旋和台风活动的气候学研究进展</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2013-dqkx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2013-dqkx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;本文主要综述和回顾了近年来季风系统研究中心关于西北太平洋热带气旋和台风(TCs)活动的气候学研究进展及有关的国内外研究。文中不仅回顾了最近关于夏、秋季西北太平洋利于TCs生成的大尺度环流型及其与涡旋的正压能量交换、西北太平洋TCs活动的年际和年代际及季节内的变化特征、以及今后全球变暖背景下西北太平洋TCs活动的变化趋势的气候学研究进展,而且综述了西北太平洋季风槽及热带对流耦合波动对西北太平洋上TCs生成的动力作用的研究。此外,文中还指出今后有关西北太平洋TCs活动一些亟需进一步研究的气候学问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;冯涛&lt;/strong&gt;, 黄荣辉, 陈光华, 武亮, 黄平, 王磊, 2013: 近年来关于西北太平洋热带气旋和台风活动的气候学研究进展. 大气科学, &lt;strong&gt;37,&lt;/strong&gt; 364-382.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
