<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>T. Feng | Welcome</title>
    <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/t.-feng/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tfeng7.github.io/author/t.-feng/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>T. Feng</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tfeng7.github.io/images/icon_hu9dc07378506dda20152aae5397c06783_79375_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>T. Feng</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/t.-feng/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of Tropical Cyclone Activity over the South China Sea: Local and Nonlocal Tropical Cyclones.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-tao/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2020-tao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, J.-M. Chen, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2020: Characteristics of Tropical Cyclone Activity over the South China Sea: Local and Nonlocal Tropical Cyclones. &lt;em&gt;Terrestrial, Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt;, 261-271, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3319/TAO.2019.07.01.02&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3319/TAO.2019.07.01.02&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The upper ocean thermodynamic and biological responses to two sequential tropical cyclones (TCs) over the Northwestern Pacific Ocean were investigated using multi-satellite datasets, in situ observations and numerical model outputs. During Kalmaegi and Fung-Wong, three distinct cold patches were observed at sea surface. The locations of these cold patches are highly correlated with relatively shallower depth of the 26 °C isotherm and mixed layer depth (MLD) and lower upper ocean heat content. The enhancement of surface chlorophyll a (chl-a) concentration was detected in these three regions as well, mainly due to the TC-induced mixing and upwelling as well as the terrestrial runoff. Moreover, the pre-existing ocean cyclonic eddy (CE) has been found to significantly modulate the magnitude of surface cooling and chl-a increase. With the deepening of the MLD on the right side of TCs, the temperature of the mixed layer decreased and the salinity increased. The sequential TCs had superimposed effects on the upper ocean response. The possible causes of sudden track change in sequential TCs scenario were also explored. Both atmospheric and oceanic conditions play noticeable roles in abrupt northward turning of the subsequent TC Fung-Wong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ning, J., Q. Xu*, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, H. Zhang, T. Wang, 2019: Upper Ocean Response to Two Sequential Tropical Cyclones over the Northwestern Pacific Ocean. &lt;em&gt;Remote Sensing&lt;/em&gt;, 11, 2431, doi:10.3390/rs11202431.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-sces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-sces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2018 typhoon season in the western North Pacific (WNP) was highly active, with 26 named tropical cyclones (TCs) from June to November, which exceeded the climatological mean (22) and was the second busiest season over the past twenty years. More TCs formed in the eastern region of the WNP and the northern region of the South China Sea (SCS). More TCs took the northeast quadrant in the WNP, recurving from northwestward to northward and causing heavy damages in mainland China (69.73 billion yuan) in 2018. Multiscale climate variability is conducive to an active season via an enhanced monsoon trough and a weakened subtropical high in the WNP. The large-scale backgrounds in 2018 showed a favorable environment for TCs established by a developing central Pacific (CP) El Niño and positive Pacific meridional mode (PMM) episode on interannual timescales. The tropical central Pacific (TCP) SST forcing exhibits primary control on TCs in the WNP and large-scale circulations, which are insensitive to the PMM. During CP El Niño years, anomalous convection associated with the TCP warming leads to significantly increased anomalous cyclonic circulation in the WNP because of a Gill-type Rossby wave response. As a result, the weakened subtropical high and enhanced monsoon trough shift eastward and northward, which favor TC genesis and development. Although such increased TC activity in 2018 might be slightly suppressed by interdecadal climate variability, it was mostly attributed to the favorable interannual background. In addition, high-frequency climate signals, such as intraseasonal oscillations (ISOs) and synoptic-scale disturbances (SSDs), interacted with the enhanced monsoon trough and strongly modulated regional TC genesis and development in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;*, and Y. Tang, 2019: Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018. &lt;em&gt;Sci. China Earth Sci.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11430-019-9474-4&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11430-019-9474-4&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reply to Comment by Michael K. Tippett on “On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.”</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-jgra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-jgra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tippett (2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD029345&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2018JD029345&lt;/a&gt;) provides an insightful comment on the theoretical consideration part of Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002),&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002),&lt;/a&gt; which studied the relationship between probabilistic and deterministic skills in dynamical seasonal climate prediction. The author connects the theoretical finding of Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;) with some previous studies on this topic and further provide a simple‐form approximation to the derived theoretical relation in Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002)&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002)&lt;/a&gt;. However, the author also indicates the difference between the considerations in Yang et al. (2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;) and the previous studies. In this reply, we present a detailed explanation to the readers of the difference between these considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang, D., X.-Q. Yang*, D. Ye, X. Sun, J. Fang, C. Chu, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Jiang, J. Liang, X. Ren, Y. Zhang, Y. Tang, 2019: Reply to Comment by Michael K. Tippett on “On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;124&lt;/strong&gt;, 3982–3983, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD030289&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JD030289&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causes of the active typhoon season in 2016 following a strong El Niño with a comparison to 1998</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-joc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-joc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article analysed two typhoon seasons (1998 and 2016) over the western North Pacific (WNP) with similar preceding background conditions of the tropical Pacific sea surface temperature (SST). Following the strong El Niño event in the preceding winter, the typhoon season was inactive in 1998 while active in 2016. Compared with 1998, the monsoon trough (MT) in 2016 shifted more eastwards, leading to an increase of the mid‐level water vapour, lower‐tropospheric relative vorticity and upper‐tropospheric divergence, and a decrease of the vertical wind shear. Additionally, the eastwards extension of the MT in 2016 induced more active tropical depression (TD)‐type waves than those in 1998. The analysis of the energy budget suggested that the eastwards shift of the MT during the 2016 typhoon season provided increased eddy kinetic energy for typhoon genesis, due to the joint contributions of the meridional shear of the mean zonal winds and the zonal wind convergence over the WNP. Moreover, the WNP entered a La Niña‐like SST pattern after July 2016. The relatively slower developing process of this pattern sustained the warmer SST anomalies and the anomalous cyclonic circulation, which the eastwards extension of the MT can be attributed. Hence, compared to 1998, the active typhoon season in 2016 is attributed to the eastwards extension of the MT, more active TD‐type wave activities, and slow developing process of a La Niña‐like SST pattern in 2016 typhoon season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huangfu, J.*, R. Huang, W. Chen, and &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018: Causes of the active typhoon season in 2016 following a strong El Niño with a comparison to 1998. &lt;em&gt;Int. J. Climatol&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;38&lt;/strong&gt;, 1107–1118, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5437&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1002/joc.5437&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Two Types of El Niño on Tropical Cyclones over the Western North Pacific: Sensitivity to Location and Intensity of Pacific Warming</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The present study investigates the impact of various central Pacific (CP) and eastern Pacific (EP) warming on tropical cyclones (TCs) over the western North Pacific (WNP) for the period 1948–2015 based on observational and reanalysis data. Four distinctly different forms of tropical Pacific warming are identified to examine different impacts of locations and intensity of tropical Pacific warming on the WNP TCs. It is shown that WNP TC activity related to ENSO shows stronger sensitivity to the intensity of CP SST warming. The locations of TC genesis in an extreme EP El Niño featuring concurrent strong CP and EP warming (CEPW) display a notable southeastward shift that is generally similar to the CP El Niño featuring CP warming alone (CPW). These influences are clearly different from the effects of moderate EP El Niño associated with EP warming alone (EPW). The above influences of Pacific warming on TCs possibly occur via atmospheric circulation variability. Anomalous convection associated with CP SST warming drives anomalous low-level westerlies away from the equator as a result of a Gill-type Rossby wave response, leading to an enhanced broad-zone, eastward-extending monsoon trough (MT). An anomalous Walker circulation in response to EP SST warming drives an increase in anomalous equatorial westerlies over the WNP, leading to a narrow-zone, slightly equatorward shift of the eastward-extending MT. These changes in the MT coincide with a shift in large-scale environments and synoptic-scale perturbations, which favor TC genesis and development. In addition, during weaker EP SST warming (WEPW) with similar intensity to CPW, local SST forcing exhibits primary control on WNP TCs and atmospheric circulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wu, L.*, H. Zhang, J.-M. Chen, and &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, 2018: Impact of Two Types of El Niño on Tropical Cyclones over the Western North Pacific: Sensitivity to Location and Intensity of Pacific Warming. &lt;em&gt;J. Climate&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;31&lt;/strong&gt;, 1725–1742, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-17-0298.1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-17-0298.1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jgra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2018-jgra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite the gradually increasing emphasis on assessing the skill of dynamical seasonal climate predictions from the probabilistic perspective, there is a lack of in‐depth understanding that an inherent relationship may exist between the probabilistic and deterministic seasonal forecast skills. In this study, we focus on investigating this relationship, through theoretical consideration based on an analytical approach and diagnostic analysis of the historical forecasts produced by multiple dynamical models. The probabilistic forecast skill is gauged in terms of its two different attributes: resolution and reliability, while the deterministic forecast skill is measured in terms of anomaly correlation (AC). Through the theoretical consideration under certain simplified assumptions, a nonlinear, monotonic relationship is analytically derived between the resolution and the AC. Subsequent diagnostic analysis shows that the resolution and AC skills of both the multimodel ensemble and its member single models indeed appear to be approximately monotonically and nonlinearly related, specifically when they are calculated in a zonally aggregated manner by which the impact of finite sample size is reduced. This observed relationship has a specific form that is consistent with what the theory predicts. In short, the theoretical result is well verified by the dynamical model forecasts. Diagnostic analysis also shows that no good relationship exists between the reliability and the AC, signifying the difference of reliability and resolution in nature. A specific application of the proven resolution‐AC coherence is also demonstrated. The proved resolution‐AC relationship can facilitate comparisons among various assessments of seasonal climate prediction skill from the deterministic or probabilistic perspective alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang, D., X.-Q. Yang*, D. Ye, X. Sun, J. Fang, C. Chu, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, Y. Jiang, J. Liang, X. Ren, Y. Zhang, Y. Tang, 2018: On the Relationship Between Probabilistic and Deterministic Skills in Dynamical Seasonal Climate Prediction. &lt;em&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Atmospheres&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;123&lt;/strong&gt;, 5261–5283, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1029/2017JD028002&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the tropical Pacific and Indian Ocean warming since the late 1970s on wintertime Northern Hemispheric atmospheric circulation and East Asian climate interdecadal changes</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Observation reveals that the tropical Pacific-Indian Ocean (TPIO) has experienced a pronounced interdecadal warming since the end of the 1970s. Meanwhile, the wintertime midlatitude Northern Hemispheric atmospheric circulation and East Asian climate have also undergone substantial interdecadal changes. The effect of the TPIO warming on these interdecadal changes are identified by a suite of AMIP-type atmospheric general circulation model experiments in which the model is integrated from September 1948 to December 1999 with prescribed historical, observed realistic sea surface temperature (SST) in a specific region and climatological SST elsewhere. Results show that the TPIO warming reproduces quite well the observed Northern Hemispheric wintertime interdecadal changes, suggesting that these interdecadal changes primarily originate from the TPIO warming. However, each sub-region of TPIO has its own distinct contribution. Comparatively, the tropical central-eastern Pacific (TCEP) and tropical western Pacific (TWP) warming makes dominant contributions to the observed positive-phase PNA-like interdecadal anomaly over the North Pacific sector, while the tropical Indian Ocean (TIO) warming tends to cancel these contributions. Meanwhile, the TIO and TWP warming makes dominant contributions to the observed positive NAO-like interdecadal anomaly over the North Atlantic sector as well as the interdecadal anomalies over the Eurasian sector, although the TWP warming’s contribution is relatively small. These remote responses are directly attributed to the TPIO warming-induced tropical convection, rainfall and diabatic heating increases, in which the TIO warming has the most significant effect. Moreover, the TPIO warming excites a Gill-type pattern anomaly over the tropical western Pacific, with a low-level anticyclonic circulation anomaly over the Philippine Sea. Of three sub-regions, the TIO warming dominates such a pattern, although the TWP warming tends to cancel this effect. The anticyclonic circulation anomaly intensifies the southwesterly flow that transfers more moisture from the Bay of Bengal to East Asia and considerably increases the winter precipitation over the southern East Asia. This is strongly supported by the observational fact that there has been a significant interdecadal increase of winter precipitation over the southern China since the end of the 1970s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chu, C., X.-Q. Yang*, X. Sun, D. Yang, Y. Jiang, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; and J. Liang, 2017: Effect of the tropical Pacific and Indian Ocean warming since the late 1970s on wintertime Northern Hemispheric atmospheric circulation and East Asian climate interdecadal changes. &lt;em&gt;Clim. Dyn.&lt;/em&gt;, doi:10.1007/s00382-017-3790-y. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00382-017-3790-y&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00382-017-3790-y&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdecadal variation of tropical cyclone genesis and its relationship to the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-ijc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2017-ijc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using the European Centre for Medium‐Range Weather Forecasts Interim Reanalysis data set and the tropical cyclone (TC) best track data obtained from the International Best Tracks Archive for Climate Stewardship project from June to November for the epoch of 1979–2013, this study reexamines the recent interdecadal shift in TC genesis over the western North Pacific (WNP) in the late 1990s. An interdecadal decrease in the frequency of the WNP TC genesis was observed during 1998–2013 compared to the period of 1979–1997. The spatial distribution of the interdecadal decrease of the WNP TC genesis running northwest‐southeast, consistent with the monsoon trough (MT) zone. The results imply that the WNP genesis may be closely related to the MT on the interdecadal timescale. After the late 1990s, the intensity of the WNP MT becomes weaker and it extends more westward, thereby providing an unfavourable condition for the TC genesis. Through a diagnosis of the energetics, we suggested that the barotropic energy conversion in the eastern part of the WNP MT tends to be weakened in the late 1990s, hence less energy to support the WNP TC genesis. Both the meridional shear and the convergence of the mean zonal winds over the eastern WNP MT have an important impact on the conversion from mean kinetic energy to eddy kinetic energy, which can be considered as the atmospheric cause of the interdecadal decrease of TC genesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huangfu, J.*, R. Huang, W. Chen, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; and L. Wu, 2017: Interdecadal variation of tropical cyclone genesis and its relationship to the monsoon trough over the western North Pacific. International Journal of Climatology, 37, 3587–3596, doi:10.1002/joc.4939.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdecadal change of summer precipitation over Eastern China around the late-1990s and associated circulation anomalies, internal dynamical causes</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2013-csb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2013-csb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Huang, R., Y. Liu,  &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; 2013: Interdecadal change of summer precipitation over Eastern China around the late-1990s and associated circulation anomalies, internal dynamical causes. &lt;em&gt;Chin. Sci. Bull.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;58,&lt;/strong&gt; 1339-1349.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interdecadal change of summer precipitation over Eastern China around the late-1990s and associated circulation anomalies, internal dynamical causes.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2014-rdqx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2014-rdqx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Huang, R., Y. Liu,  &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng,&lt;/strong&gt; 2013: Interdecadal change of summer precipitation over Eastern China around the late-1990s and associated circulation anomalies, internal dynamical causes. &lt;em&gt;Chin. Sci. Bull.&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;58,&lt;/strong&gt; 1339-1349.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
