<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ning J. | Welcome</title>
    <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/ning-j./</link>
      <atom:link href="https://tfeng7.github.io/author/ning-j./index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ning J.</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://tfeng7.github.io/images/icon_hu9dc07378506dda20152aae5397c06783_79375_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Ning J.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/author/ning-j./</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tropical cyclones and multiscale climate variability: The active western North Pacific Typhoon season of 2018.</title>
      <link>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-rs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tfeng7.github.io/publication/2019-rs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The upper ocean thermodynamic and biological responses to two sequential tropical cyclones (TCs) over the Northwestern Pacific Ocean were investigated using multi-satellite datasets, in situ observations and numerical model outputs. During Kalmaegi and Fung-Wong, three distinct cold patches were observed at sea surface. The locations of these cold patches are highly correlated with relatively shallower depth of the 26 °C isotherm and mixed layer depth (MLD) and lower upper ocean heat content. The enhancement of surface chlorophyll a (chl-a) concentration was detected in these three regions as well, mainly due to the TC-induced mixing and upwelling as well as the terrestrial runoff. Moreover, the pre-existing ocean cyclonic eddy (CE) has been found to significantly modulate the magnitude of surface cooling and chl-a increase. With the deepening of the MLD on the right side of TCs, the temperature of the mixed layer decreased and the salinity increased. The sequential TCs had superimposed effects on the upper ocean response. The possible causes of sudden track change in sequential TCs scenario were also explored. Both atmospheric and oceanic conditions play noticeable roles in abrupt northward turning of the subsequent TC Fung-Wong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ning, J., Q. Xu*, &lt;strong&gt;T. Feng&lt;/strong&gt;, H. Zhang, T. Wang, 2019: Upper Ocean Response to Two Sequential Tropical Cyclones over the Northwestern Pacific Ocean. &lt;em&gt;Remote Sensing&lt;/em&gt;, 11, 2431, doi:10.3390/rs11202431.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
